Andrew Eisenberg collection of East African commercial sound recordings AD.MC.035
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
Andrew Eisenberg collection of East African commercial sound recordings
circa 1930-1975
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
Eisenberg, Andrew J.
AD.MC.035
48
504 audio_recordings
The Andrew Eisenberg collection of East African commercial sound recordings contains sound files and associated metadata for hundreds of commercial sound recordings produced for East African audiences, and in particular, African and Arab audiences of the Swahili Coast, between the late 1920s and the first decade of the twenty-first century.
Biographical note
Andrew J. Eisenberg is assistant professor of music at New York University Abu Dhabi (NYUAD). Prior to arriving at NYUAD, he held teaching positions at Northwestern University, Stony Brook University, and Bard College. A musical ethnographer and sound culture researcher specializing in urban Africa and the Indian Ocean world, Eisenberg received his PhD in ethnomusicology from Columbia University in 2009, and carried out postdoctoral research between 2010 and 2013 as a participant in the European Research Council's "Music, Digitization, Mediation" project led by Professor Georgina Born at Oxford University.
Much of Andrew Eisenberg's published and forthcoming scholarship focuses on issues of voice, place, and identity on Kenya's "Swahili coast." In recent years, he has also been carrying out ethnographic research on the music recording industry in the Kenyan capital Nairobi.
Conditions governing access
Materials can be accessed at the Archives and Special Collections Reading Room of the NYUAD Library, and can also, in some circumstances, be accessed remotely.
In order to access the collection remotely, there are two options depending on the affiliation of the user.
For students, faculty, and other users affiliated with New York University, click on the following link and supply your university NetID and password:
https://nyu.box.com/v/eisenberg-nyu
For all other users, please click on the following link to access a form, which when completed, will be submitted for review:
https://goo.gl/forms/A7CoxIh8pxDK9SfJ3
If remote use of the collection is approved, a separate password will be supplied to provide access.
Immediate source of acquisition
Gift of Andrew J. Eisenberg, 2016-2017.
Related materials
Andrew Eisenberg and his colleagues at New York University Abu Dhabi (and elsewhere), have also partnered with local institutions in Kenya and Tanzania during their research, and plan to place copies of this collection in several such institutions. To date, one copy of this collection has been placed with the Dhow Countries Music Academy in Zanzibar.
Scope and contents note
The Andrew Eisenberg collection of East African commercial sound recordings contains sound files and associated metadata for hundreds of commercial sound recordings produced for East African audiences, and in particular, African and Arab audiences of the Swahili Coast, between the late 1920s and the first decade of the twenty-first century.
Dr. Andrew J. Eisenberg collected these materials in Mombasa, Kenya, between 2004 and 2006, with the assistance of local collector Jamal Hafidh Jahadhmy.
Most of the recordings in the collection fall within the realm of Swahili-language urban popular music. There are also examples of rural music traditions, colonial-era martial music, recited Swahili poetry, and Swahili comedy sketches.
The collection is comprised of three series:
Series 1: Digital audio captured from 78 r.p.m. records. The source recordings belong to a private collector in Mombasa, Kenya, who wishes to remain anonymous.
Series 2: Digital audio captured from audio cassette recordings of 78- and 45-r.p.m. records. These cassettes belong to Jamal Hafidh Jahadhmy, who created them by carefully transferring the audio recordings from records held in private collections in Mombasa, Kenya.
Series 3: Digital audio transferred from commercially produced audiocassette recordings acquired by Eisenberg in Mombasa between 2004 and 2006.
Popular music -- Kenya; Mombasa (Kenya)
- Series I: Private collector (anonymous) - 78's, circa 1930-1965; 8440; PP; 313 audio_recordings
  Scope note
  Series 1: Digital audio captured from 78 r.p.m. records. The source recordings belong to a private collector in Mombasa, Kenya, who wishes to remain anonymous.
  - Aborosi and Party, 12433
    - Aborosi & Party: Huyu Mwana Makundisha, circa 1955-1965; 8445; 1 audio_recording 15.7 MB (Folder 1)
      Physical characteristics of original
      Serial number: Mzuri, AB 19, AM 10. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:58.
    - Aborosi & Party: Ngiyangu Yedi, circa 1955-1965; 8446; 1 audio_recording 14.4 MB (Folder 2)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AB 20, AM 10. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:43.
  - Adam Salim and Trio, 12434
    - Adam Salim Trio: Jambo Sigara Baridi, N/A; 8450; 1 audio_recording 15.4 MB (Folder 3)
      Serial number: Columbia, CES.960, EO.2107. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:54.
    - Adam Salim Trio: Mola Akipenda, N/A; 8755; 1 audio_recording 15.1 MB (Folder 4)
      Serial number: Columbia, CES 961, EO.2107. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration:
    - Adam Salim Trio: Sili Waklikwa Mesta, N/A; 8444; 1 audio_recording 16.1 MB (Folder 5)
      Serial number: Columbia, CES.964, EO.2108. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:20.
    - Adam Salim Trio: Teusi Wangu Mzuri, N/A; 8447; 1 audio_recording 15.0 MB (Folder 6)
      Serial number: Columbia, CES.965, EO.2108. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:50.
    - Adam Salim & Party: Alipokuwa Safiriri, N/A; 8448; 1 audio_recording 15.8 MB (Folder 7)
      Serial number: Columbia, CES.1150, EO.2148. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:59.
    - Adam Salim & Party: Toto Zuri, N/A; 8449; 1 audio_recording 15.2 MB (Folder 8)
      Physical characteristics
      Serial number: Columbia, CES.1151, EO.2148. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:52.
  - African City Band, 12438
    - African City Band: Peni Langu, N/A; 8443; 1 audio_recording 15.3 MB (Folder 9)
      Serial number: Columbia, CES.978, EO.2136. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:53.
    - African City Band: Tulipokuwa Tukipendana, 8463; 1 audio_recording 15.8 MB (Folder 10)
      Physical characteristics of the original:
      Serial number: Columbia, CES.979, EO.2136. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:58.
  - Agey Jazz Orchestra, 12439
    - Agey Jazz Orchestra. Gerechabo Adolf & Party: Tuache Ubaya, circa 1955-1965; 8801; 1 audio_recording 14.3 MB (Folder 11)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AB.1026, AM 513. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:42.
    - Agey Jazz Orchestra, Gerechabo Adolf and Party: Uniache Nicheze Mambo, circa 1955-1965; 8814; 1 audio_recording 14.0 MB (Folder 12)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AB.1025, AM 513. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes from label: Recorded by Assanand & Sons (Mombasa) LTD. Duration: 2:38.
  - Akida bin Kheri, 12473
    - Akida Bin Kheri: La Fuadi Part 1, circa 1930; 8464; 1 audio_recording 15.5 MB (Folder 13)
      Serial number: Columbia, WE 48, W 63131. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Collector (source of recording) provided information that melody was written by Maalim Shaaban. Duration: 2:55.
    - Akida Bin Kheri: La Fuadi Part 2, circa 1930; 8465; 1 audio_recording 15.0 MB (Folder 14)
      Serial number: Columbia, WE 48, W 63132. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Collector (source of recording) provided information that melody was written by Maalim Shaaban. Duration: 2:49.
  - Ali Abdulla, 12600
    - Ali Abdulla: Tangu Jana, 8496; 1 audio_recording 17.8 MB (Folder 15)
      Serial number: Columbia, CES.1308, EO.501. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:22.
  - Ali and Party, 12601
    - Ali & Party: Anyi wa Khiari, 1938-1946; 8495; 1 audio_recording 17.9 MB (Folder 16)
      Serial number: HMV, OAF 25, MA.13. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:22.
  - Aratibu Bocho, 12602
    - Aratibu Bocho Na Ngoma Ya Changani: Sifaidi Mtwali, circa 1930; 8497; 1 audio_recording 15.0 MB (Folder 17)
      Physical characteristics of original:
      Serial number: Columbia, WE 38, W 63144. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:49.
  - Asumani Bini Sumaili, 12472
    - Asumani Bini Sumaili: Chaupele Mpenzi, N/A; 8500; 1 audio_recording 14.7 MB (Folder 18)
      Serial number: Gallotone, GB .1336, RC.32, XYZ.6166. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:46
    - Asumani Bini Sumaili: Sitaki kelele bibi nendazako, N/A; 8501; 1 audio_recording 12.5 MB (Folder 19)
      Serial number: Gallotone, GB.1336, RC.32. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:21.
  - Banusaada Lele-Mama, 12440
    - Banusaada Lele-Mama: Haiba Banusaada, 1947-1951; 8507; 1 audio_recording 16.7 MB (Folder 20)
      Serial number: Jambo, JR.653, EA.276. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:34
    - Banusaada Lele-Mama: Niwarembo, 1947-1951; 8509; 1 audio_recording 16.8 MB (Folder 21)
      Serial number: Jambo, JR.652, EA.276 Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:10.
    - Banusaada Lele-Mama: Asantu Spiringi, circa 1947-1951; 8506; 1 audio_recording 17.8 MB (Folder 22)
      Serial number: Jambo, JR.655, EA.277 Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:21.
    - Banusaada Lele-Mama: Sore Bibi, circa 1947-1951; 8508; 1 audio_recording 17.0 MB (Folder 23)
      Serial number: Jambo, JR.654, EA.277. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:12.
  - Ben and Party, 12599
    - Ben & Party: Simba wa Mombasa, N/A; 8510; 1 audio_recording 18.7 MB (Folder 24)
      Serial number: Columbia, CES.1315, EO.2176. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:32.
  - Bernadette Sakina, 12471
    - Bernadette Sakina, et les guitaristes A. Artour et Amundala Amiri: Bwa Camilla Mpenzi, 8512; 1 audio_recording 14.6 MB (Folder 25)
      Serial number: Fiesta, CF 303, 240. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:45.
    - Bernadette Sakina, et les guitaristes A. Artour et Amundala Amiri: Kaka Mpenzi Mwezi Unaisha, 8513; 1 audio_recording 14.0 MB (Folder 26)
      Serial number: Fiesta, CF 302, 240. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:38.
  - Bin Berek, 12441
    - Bin Berek: Basamir Azzein—Part 1, circa 1955-1965; 8441; 1 audio_recording 13.9 MB (Folder 27)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM 499, AB.997. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Alternate spelling: Ahmed Mahfouz Bin Brek. Duration: 2:37
    - Bin Berek: Basamir Azzein—Part 2, circa 1955-1965; 8442; 1 audio_recording 13.9 MB (Folder 28)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM 499, AB.998. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Alternate spelling: Ahmed Mahfouz Bin Brek. Duration: 2:37.
    - Bin Berek: Banatlub El-Mola--Side B, circa 1955-1965; 8514; 1 audio_recording 14.4 MB (Folder 29)
      Serial number: Mzuri AM.572, ABC 22758. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Alternate spelling: Ahmed Mahfouz Bin Brek. Duration: 2:43.
    - Bin Berek: Banatlub El-Mola--Side A, circa 1955-1965; 8515; 1 audio_recording 14.7 MB (Folder 30)
      Serial number: Mzuri AM.572, ABC 22757. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Alternate spelling: Ahmed Mahfouz Bin Brek. Duration: 2:46.
  - Bryan Rimber and Party, 12464
    - Bryan Rimber and Party: Mapenzi ya Asubuhi - Side B, circa 1955-1965; 8516; 1 audio_recording 14.7 MB (Folder 31)
      Serial number: Mzuri AM.361, A.B 728. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:46.
    - Bryan Rimber and Party: Rudi Ana - Side A, circa 1955-1965; 8517; 1 audio_recording 14.4 MB (Folder 32)
      Serial number: Mzuri AM.361, A.B. 727. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:43.
  - Buda, 12465
    - Buda: Beishara—Comedy, N/A; 8518; 1 audio_recording 19.0 MB (Folder 33)
      Serial number: Columbia EO.2157, CES.4138. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:35.
    - Buda: Ukosapo Darihima, N/A; 8519; 1 audio_recording 17.7 MB (Folder 34)
      Serial number: Columbia EO.2157, CES.4139. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:20.
  - Budda bin Mwendo, 12466
    - Budda Bin Mwendo: Usingizi. Part 1, circa 1930; 8520; 1 audio_recording 14.7 MB (Folder 35)
      Serial number: Columbia, WE.56, W.63055. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Alternate spelling: "Buda Bin Mwendo." Duration: 2:46.
    - Budda Bin Mwendo: Usingizi. Part 2, circa 1930; 8521; 1 audio_recording 14.7 MB (Folder 36)
      Serial number: Columbia, WE.56, W.63056. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Alternate spelling: "Buda Bin Mwendo." Duration: 2:46.
  - Chuba and Party, 12598
    - Chuba & Party: Kiko Mboli, 1938-1946; 8522; 1 audio_recording 16.6 MB (Folder 37)
      Serial number: HMV, MA.59, OAF.215. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Artist also known as Chuba Shee. Title should read: "Kiko Mbali." Duration: 3:08.
  - Coast Social Orchestra, 12442
    - The Coast Social Orchestra: Moyo wanitanga-tanga, N/A; 8707; 1 audio_recording 14.2 MB (Folder 38)
      Serial number: Gallotone, GB.1894, XYZ.7297. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Leader: A. Ayub Gombe. Duration: 2:40.
      Swahili rumba
    - The Coast Social Orchestra: Sini kere kere, omama, 1952; 8795; 1 audio_recording 15.9 MB (Folder 39)
      Serial number: Gallotone GB.1894, XYZ.7296. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Leader: A. Ayub Gombe. Duration: 2:59.
    - Coast Social Orchestra: Napenda, 1950; 8729; 1 audio_recording 13.4 MB (Folder 40)
      Serial number: Gallotone, GB.1899, XYZ.7657. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Leader: A. Ayub Gombe. Duration: 2:32.
    - Coast Social Orchestra: Tulipokuwa tukipendana, 1950; 8803; 1 audio_recording 14.1 MB (Folder 41)
      Serial number: Gallotone, GB.1899, XYZ.7658. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Leader: A. Ayub Gombe. Duration: 2:39.
  - Cubano Marimbo, 12463
    - Cubano Marimbo: Siri Mlofanya Nyumbani, 1952-1961; 8523; 1 audio_recording 14.2 MB (Folder 42)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.559, J.R. 1161. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:40.
    - Cubano Marimbo: Wawa, 1952-1961; 8524; 1 audio_recording 13.9 MB (Folder 43)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.559, J.R. 116. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:37.
  - Dar es Salaam Jazz Band, 12443
    - Dar es Salaam Jazz Band: Chama nikiingiya - Side A, N/A; 8531; 1 audio_recording 13.6 MB (Folder 44)
      Physical characteristics of the original
      Serial number: Gallotone, GB.1247, XYZ.6606, RC.31. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:39.
    - Dar es Salaam Jazz Band: Machapa - Side B, N/A; XYZ.6067; 8532; 1 audio_recording 13.5 MB (Folder 45)
      Serial number: Gallotone, GB.1247, XYZ.6067, RC.31. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:33.
    - Dar es Salaam Jazz Band: Ewe Mpenzi Wangu - Side B, N/A; 8525; 1 audio_recording 13.7 MB (Folder 46)
      Serial number: Gallotone, GB.2231, ABC.13801. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:35.
    - Dar es Salaam Jazz Band: Shari La Moyoni Mwao - Side A, N/A; 8526; 1 audio_recording 13.5 MB (Folder 47)
      Serial number: Gallotone, GB.2231, ABC.13798. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:33.
    - Dar es Salaam Jazz Band: Tangu Hapo Mwatujuwa - Side B, N/A; 8527; 1 audio_recording 13.4 MB (Folder 48)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      Serial number: Gallotone, GB.2248, ABC.13800. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:31.
    - Dar es Salaam Jazz Band: Yawapasa Kukumbuka - Side A, N/A; 8528; 1 audio_recording 13.8 MB (Folder 49)
      Serial number: Gallotone, GB.2248, ABC.13799. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:36.
    - Dar es Salaam Jazz Band: Kula ni sili nakwambia - Side A, 8529; 1 audio_recording 14.4 MB (Folder 50)
      Serial number: Gallotone, TA.66, ABC.12294. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:43.
    - Dar es Salaam Jazz Band: Maneno yako we mpenzi - Side B, N/A; 8530; 1 audio_recording 14.1 MB (Folder 51)
      Serial number: Gallotone, TA.66, ABC.12295. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:40.
    - Dar es Salaam Jazz Band: Mna Tuonea Bure Dar, 1952-1961; 8533; 1 audio_recording 12.8 MB (Folder 52)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.546, J.R. 1134. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:24.
    - Dar es-Salaam Jazz Band: Nyote Mwajua Yakini Dar, 1952-1961; 8534; 1 audio_recording 13.3 MB (Folder 53)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.546, J.R. 1135. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:30.
  - Egyptian Musical Club, 12444
    - Egyptian Musical Club: Baladi Yalkhali, N/A; 8535; 1 audio_recording 15.4 MB (Folder 54)
      Serial number: Gallotone, GB.2247, ABC.13803. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:54.
    - Egyptian Musical Club: Abbas Song - Side B, N/A; 8548; 1 audio_recording 15.5 MB (Folder 55)
      Serial number: Gallotone, GB.2247, ABC.13805. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:56.
    - Egyptian Musical Club: Mauwa, N/A; 8683; 1 audio_recording 15.3 MB (Folder 56)
      Serial number: Gallotone, TA.70, ABC.12285. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:52.
    - Egyptian Musical Club: Yarabi nihifadhi, N/A; 8837; 1 audio_recording 16.0 MB (Folder 57)
      Serial number: Gallotone, TA.70, ABC.12290. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:10.
    - Egyptian Musical Club, with Abbas Haji (vocalist): Yailahi Duwa, circa 1952-1961; 8832; 1 audio_recording 16.4 MB (Folder 58)
      Serial number: Jambo, EA.555, J.R. 1152. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:05.
    - Egyptian Club (Abbas Haji): Kupenda Ni Mashaka, circa 1955-1965; 8641; 1 audio_recording 14.4 MB (Folder 59)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.365, A.B. 729. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:43.
    - Egyptian Club (Abbas Haji): Mapenzi Wawili, circa 1955-1965; 8680; 1 audio_recording 14.6 MB (Folder 60)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.365, A.B. 730. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:45.
    - Egyptian Musical Club: Huba Ina Joto, circa 1955-1965; 8611; 1 audio_recording 16.4 MB (Folder 61)
      Physical characteristics of originals
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.374, A.B. 747. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:05.
    - Egyptian Musical Club: Rahat Lleli, circa 1955-1965; 8783; 1 audio_recording 15.2 MB (Folder 62)
      Serial number: Mzuri, AM.374, A.B. 748. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:52.
    - Egyptian Band: Mary Wacha Chasiya, circa 1956-1959; 8673; 1 audio_recording 16.5 MB (Folder 63)
      Serial number: Tom Tom, TR.474, T 0926. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes from label: Leaders: Sheikh Salim & Siti Nuru. Opel Gramophone Record Factory Ltd., Kampala/Uganda, East Africa. Duration: 3:07.
    - Egyptian Musical Club: Nura Nura, circa 1956-1959; 8764; 1 audio_recording 17.6 MB (Folder 64)
      Serial number: Tom Tom, TR.474, T 0927. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes on label: Leader Abbas Haji. Opel Gramophone Record Factory Ltd., Kampala/Uganda, East Africa. Duration: 3:19
  - El Antari, Saleh Abdulla, 12469
    - El Antari, Saleh Abdulla: Akhafu Akhaf Indarat, circa 1938-1946; 8550; 1 audio_recording 15.3 MB (Folder 65)
      Serial number: HMV, MA.241, OAS 383. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:53
    - El Antari, Saleh Abdulla: Wanahibak Ya Salaam, circa 1938-1946; 8823; 1 audio_recording 15.5 MB (Folder 66)
      Serial number: HMV, OAS 382, MA.241. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:55.
  - Fatuma and Party, 12603
    - Fatuma & Party: Nine Manes Matatu, circa 1938-1946; 8760; 1 audio_recording 16.7 MB (Folder 67)
      Serial number: HMV, MA.59, OAF 216. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:09.
  - Fundi Konde, 12445
    - Fundi Konde & Ben: Namapenzi Nikupendayo, 8725; 1 audio_recording 13.7 MB (Folder 68)
      Serial number: Habari, M 773, CV.16. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:34.
    - Fundi Konde & Ben: White Cap, N/A; 8830; 1 audio_recording 13.6 MB (Folder 69)
      Serial number: Habari, M 774, CV.16. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:34.
    - Fundi Konde & Ben: Hiyo Kwetu Si Sheriya, N/A; 8610; 1 audio_recording 13.8 MB (Folder 70)
      Serial number: Habari, M 776, CV 17. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:36.
    - Fundi Konde & Ben: Junda Milimani, N/A; 8618; 1 audio_recording 14.7 MB (Folder 71)
      Serial number: Habari, M 775, CV 17. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:47.
    - Fundi Konde & Ben: Dada Mariamu, N/A; 8582; 1 audio_recording 15.3 MB (Folder 72)
      Serial number: Habari, M 778, CV 18. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:52.
    - Fundi Konde & Ben: Hibaba Ingome, N/A; 8609; 1 audio_recording 14.8 MB (Folder 73)
      Serial number: Habari, M 777, CV 18. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:47.
    - Fundi Konde: Kundara Kundara, N/A; 8640; 1 audio_recording 15.1 MB (Folder 74)
      Serial number: Habari, M 780, CV 19. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 2:50.
    - Fundi Konde: Wiwu Mwingi Si Mali, N/A; 8831; 1 audio_recording 15.3 MB (Folder 75)
      Serial number: Habari, M 779, CV.19. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Other notes: Title should read: "Wivu Mwingi Si Mali." Duration: 2:53.
    - Fundi Konde, with Ben Nicholas, Ester Nicholas, Reg. Manus: Kazi Kilindini, 1957; 8511; 1 audio_recording 13.6 MB (Folder 76)
      Serial number: HMV, AMC.159, OAM.446, AMC 159. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Artists: Fundi Konde (guitar & vocal), Ester Nicholas (vocal), Ben Nicholas (vocal), Reg. Manus (P. accordeon). Duration: 2:35
    - Fundi Konde/Ester Nicholas/Ben Nicholas/Reg Manus: Josephina Josephina Josephina, 1957; 8616; 1 audio_recording 15.0 MB (Folder 77)
      Serial number: HMV, AMC.159, OAM.447. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Artists: Fundi Konde (guitar & vocal), Ester Nicholas (vocal), Ben Nicholas (vocal), Reg. Manus (P. accordeon). Duration: 2:49.
    - Fundi Konde and Daniel Katuga, with The Nairobi City Five: Ewe Pendo Langu, 8592; 1 audio_recording 16.4 MB (Folder 78)
      Serial number: HMV, AMC.38, OAM 66. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:05.
    - Fundi Konde and Daniel Katuga, with The Nairobi City Five: Gari La Punda Sipandi, 8597; 1 audio_recording 16.4 MB (Folder 79)
      Serial number: HMCV, AMC.38, OAM 63. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Duration: 3:06.
    - Fundi Konde/Rajabu Idi: Penzi Penzi, 1957; 8777; 1 audio_recording 14.7 MB (Folder 80)
      Serial number: HMV, AMC.141, OAM.452, AMC.141. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Artists: Rajabu Idi (guitar & vocal), Fundi Konde (guitar). Duration: 2:46.
    - Fundi Konde and Rajabu Idi: Wangapi Wataazizi, 1957; 8825; 1 audio_recording 15.0 MB (Folder 81)
      Serial number: HMV, AMC.141, OAM.453. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Rajabu Idi (guitar & vocal), Fundi Konde (guitar). Duration: 2:49.
    - Fundi Konde/R. Manus: Oh! Mama Lady Oh!, 1957; 8768; 1 audio_recording 14.8 MB (Folder 82)
      Serial number: HMV, AMC.151, OAM.445. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Artists: Fundi Konde (guitar & vocal), R. Manus (P. Accordeon). Duration: 2:47
    - Fundi Konde/Reg. Manus/Ben Nicholas: Zum Zum Zum, 1957; 8841; 1 audio_recording 13.4 MB (Folder 83)
      Serial number: HMV, AMC.151, OAM.448. Original format: 78 rpm shellac disc. Artists: Fundi Konde (guitar & vocal), Reg. Manus (P. accordeon), Ben Nicholas (bass). Duration: 2:32.
    - Fundi Konde/Harry Makacha/Ester Nicholas/Ben Nicholas: Ndege Wote Wameruka, 1958; 8734; 1 audio_recording 15.7 MB (Folder 84)